師範代？ 師範…
His father forced him to slave away...
もしかしたら　私は…
until Gyro finally killed him and fled.
起こしてしまったのかも しれません
His father, who raised Gyro
alone, was a silent man.
ゴンが　ギドとの戦いで 重傷を負ってから１か月後
When his father returned from work, he drank cheap liquor by himself
until he went to bed.
天空闘技場では　注目の一戦が 行われようとしていた
He very rarely talked to Gyro,
who was on the upper bunk.
あっ　キルア。
how to speak before the age of seven.
今　そっちに行こうかと 思ってたとこなんだ。 おま…　ケガは　もういいのか？ うん。
When Gyro returned from work, he was not permitted to leave his bed, except when visiting the restroom.
ほら！　もうバッチリ！ 分かった　分かった。
He was allowed to relieve himself twice
a day, and only before 9 PM.
こいつ…　全治４か月のケガを たった１か月で 完治させやがった！
The bed's rotting wood creaked loudly
whenever he turned in his sleep.
ったく　どういう体してんだよ。 どういうって言われても…。
His father hated that sound.
で？　何か 用があったんじゃないの？ あぁ　これこれ…。 チケット？ ただのチケットじゃないぜ。
After his father once severely
beat him because of that noise, Gyro learned to sleep without any motion.
ヒソカ戦。 ２００階クラスの選手ってことで 優先券がとれたんだ。
He also learned to control his bladder at night, keeping an empty liquor bottle
for when he couldn't hold it.
ヒソカ戦　大人気だぜ ダフ屋まで出たくらいだ。 へぇ。
"Don't make trouble for others."
で　いろいろ情報を集めて来た。 やっぱ　ヒソカは ただ者じゃないぜ。
That was the one lesson his
silent father taught him.
１１戦して８勝３敗　６ＫＯ。 ＫＯ＝死人の数なんだってよ。 でも３回　負けてるんだ。
From a young age, Gyro did
his best to adhere to it, learning from his mistakes.
その３敗は　不戦敗だってさ。 不戦敗？ 戦闘準備期間が　なくなったから 登録だけして 試合には来なかったらしい。 ってことは　つまり…。
Since his father had never
bought him even one toy, this lesson was his one and
only gift from his father.
ヒソカは実際に戦えば 負けなしってことだ。
Within his small world,
his father was essentially God.
だね…。 その上 相手に取られたポイントは わずか４ポイント。 ダウン１回 クリーンヒット３回のみ。 実力は　間違いなく フロアマスターだってよ。
And no matter how cruel his father could be, Gyro continued to idolize him, believing that his father needed him.
うわ　参ったな！
This belief stemmed from two facts...
ったく
When Gyro was five, a terrible fever nearly killed him.
顔は　ちっとも「参った」って 言ってねえよ
All night, his father stayed up,
replacing his towels with fresh ones.
で　対戦相手は カストロってんだけど
And the other reason was...
２年前に　こいつが　唯一 ヒソカからダウンを奪ってる男だ。
that his father had never
once ordered him to leave.
しかも　このダウンを含めて ヒソカが取られた ４ポイントのうち ３ポイントが　こいつからなんだ。
Gyro was proud of these two facts.
ヒソカから３ポイントも…。
"Idiot...
因縁の対決ってやつだな。
He hasn't kicked you out
because you bring in money!"
どうやら　お互い　申し合わせて 戦闘日を指定したらしい。 ふん。 これで多少は　ヒソカの戦い方が 分析できるぜ。 本気のヒソカが見られるかもよ。 うん。
Though he had previously kept that
possibility locked away deep in his mind, Gyro snapped when the older youth
insensitively brought it to light.
でも　いいのかな ウイングさんとの約束が…。
Regretting that he'd revealed his secret,
Gyro was furious with himself.
((今日から２か月間 一切の試合を禁じます)) ((「念」の修行　および「念」について 調べることも許しません))
His pride wounded, rage overcame
him, and he attacked the youth.
大丈夫に決まってるだろ ただ試合を見るだけなんだから。 うえっ！ んぎゅ！ ダメです！ 試合観戦も 「念」を調べる行為に相当します。
The youth had always mocked the timid boy, so when the boy fought back,
he went mad with anger, to the point where not even
knocking him out would satisfy him.
ウイングさん…。 いきなり脅かすなよ。 ゴンくん 腕のケガは　もういいんですか？
He stomped on the boy's face, spat on him, and uttered the finishing blow:
はい！　もう大丈夫です。 何という回復力だ
"When you were sick, a neighbor took care of you!
治ったんだから 試合　見てもいいよな？
Your old man was drinking by himself as always.
いいえ　私がゴンくんに 言い渡した期間は２か月です。 え！
You were delirious, so you wouldn't know this.
ゴンくん　君は　あと１か月 「点」のみの修行と 万全の回復に専念しなさい。
But that night, the neighbor had
a fight with your old man.
あっ　はい　分かりました。
He asked your dad what he'd do if his kid died.
じゃ　そういうことで。 オス！　お大事に。
Let me tell you what your old man said.
しゃあねえな 試合は録画しとくとして
It wouldn't matter. I don't care if he dies. You hear that?"
俺だけでも見て来るか。 うん！ 「点」のみを 毎日　行っているようだ
As Gyro listened to the youth, he witnessed something inconceivable.
彼らの　それは 静寂の大河を彷彿とさせる 師範代？ ん？
His father looked him in the eye, paid him no attention, and then left.
あ　いえ…　何でもないっす。
That was when Gyro finally understood.
いかんな…　私のほうが 心を乱されているではないか
The universe doesn't give a damn about me.
[TV]　こんにちは！ アナウンサーのコッコです。
My father doesn't care if I live or die.
[TV]　本日は天空闘技場から 注目のカード！
In other words, my life has no meaning.
[TV]　カストロ対ヒソカ戦を お送りいたします！
If I live, I'll bring in money.
[TV]　まだ決戦の １時間前だというのに 会場は　すでに超満員となって…。
My father told me not to
make trouble for others
)
It was never a lesson to help his son.
((これを見て 常に約束を忘れぬように))
It was fully for his own benefit. In that lesson, "others" meant my father.
２年前に行われた 同一カードでは ヒソカ選手が勝利！ カストロ選手との リベンジを懸けた まさに因縁の対決を前に
Eventually, the boy stood up, grabbing a nearby hammer.
負けは　いずれも 欠場による不戦敗！ [TV]　休みがちの死に神 奇術師ヒソカ！
Nine years later, Gyro founded the NGL.
[TV]　片や戦績９勝１敗。 [TV]　ヒソカ選手に敗れて以来 ９連勝でフロアマスターに王手！
Nine years after that, NGL became
a nation, with him as its king.
[TV]　武闘家　カストロ！ 「借りは必ず返す」の公言通り
Gyro desired to ruin life for the entire world.
リベンジなるか？ [TV]　今　最もフロアマスターに近い 男２人による対決は 間もなくです！
The drug D² was merely the first step.
[TV] 勝算がないなら戦いませんよ。
Yunju!
[TV]　２年前とは別人だってところを お見せします。
You handed those humans over to Colt so easily.
おっ　結構　言うね。
I didn't feel like fighting.
その自信が　本物かどうか 確かめてやるぜ
I just want to enjoy the hunt.
私に何か用かい？
This is bad.
何！
These creatures are too dangerous! Look!
俺に気づかれず 素早くドアを開けて 横をすり抜け　背後に？
What...
いや！　絶対に　あり得ない！ 俺がドアから目を離したのは こいつが 背後から声をかけた後だ
What is happening in this place?
キルアくん。 えっ！
What? More dead soldiers found?
同じ２００階クラスの ライバルくらいチェックしてるよ。
Yeah, three of Zazan's were discovered.
ゴンって子は 一緒じゃないのかい？
Plus, one of mine is missing...
あら　ぜんぶ　バレバレなのね。 今日は敵情視察かい？
Its communication has been cut
off, and it hasn't returned.
いやいや　ちょっと　あんたを 近くで見たかっただけさ。
Yunju's team dealt with the
humans holding guns.
で　私の印象は　どうだい？
Does this mean there are other
humans who are resisting us?
相当やるね。
Sounds that way...
ありがとう　キルアくんの「絶」も なかなか見事だったよ。
But the dead soldiers were killed
by something that wasn't a gun.
だが気配を消すなら
Something?
この階に来る前からじゃなきゃ 意味がない。
What could it have been?
君ほどの使い手の気配が 急に消えたら 私でなくても警戒するよ。
How would I know? Probably some new weapon we haven't seen.
この階に俺が上がって来た時から チェックしてたのかよ。
Where are the corpses?
まぁね。
Peggy's examining them above.
で　聞くけど　さっきの 一体　どうやったの？
This one was killed by a gun.
残念ながら教えられないな いずれ君と戦うかもしれないしね。
I'm sure since bullets are still inside the body. But I'm not sure about the others.
安心しなよ　俺　これ以上 ここで戦う気ないから。
The skull was punctured. Yes, but not by a gun.
そうかい？　君のオーラは そうは言ってないけどな。
And I had difficulty understanding the soldiers' explanation of the events...
ハハっ　冗談だよ 答えは試合で　お見せする。
As it is, the foot soldiers' communications
are simplistic and just to the point.
「バトルオリンピア」で 待っているよ。
They said one human mimicked firing
a gun, and no projectile emerged, but something pierced the
soldier's skulls and they fell, dead.
君なら来られる。 戦う気　ねえっつうの！　フンっ！
Can't some soldiers both see
and feel what's happening? You're correct.
さぁ！　いよいよです！
So they possess abilities that we do not...
ヒソカ選手ｖｓカストロ選手 因縁の決戦！
These humans could prove tougher
opponents than anticipated.
感謝するよ　ヒソカ お前の洗礼がなければ
If humans have this power, once we
inherit their genes, we also will.
私は　ここまで強くは なれなかっただろう。
We only lack the trait. You don't understand...
言っておくが お前に敗れた後の９戦 一度として 全力で戦ったことは　ない。
The humans' strength lies
in their ability to learn. If they learn that the Queen
is where we're vulnerable, they'll do whatever it takes to kill her.
全て　お前を倒すための 準備運動にすぎない！
Hmm? You're the one who doesn't understand!
始め！ 行くぞ！　ハァ！
That just means we need to do
whatever it takes to keep her safe.
クリーンヒット！
That's right.
まずはカストロ選手の先制打が さく裂！
I will protect her... I will protect Reina!
何だ？　今のは…
Reina?
本気で来い　ヒソカ。
Who's Reina? Uh, you're the one who said that name!
先手をとったのは カストロ選手！
I didn't say anything. You must be hearing things.
素早い手刀の攻撃をよけられず ヒソカ選手 先制ポイントを奪われました！
Anyway, the problem is that humans
possess multiple weapons capable of defeating our foot soldiers.
まただ　錯覚か？
What should we do? Use their weapons against them.
２年前の私とは違う 次は容赦しない。
Give them a taste of their own medicine. Only soldiers of our rank have the capacity
to manipulate complex weaponry.
本気を出すかどうかは 僕が決める。
But the humans don't know that. They must be very frightened.
そうか… では　早めに決断することだ。
I understand...
あっ！
Reina?
ハッ！
It didn't work...
どうした？　逃げるばかりで 攻撃して来ないのか？
That means all the other Hunters I was
in contact with have been taken out. Oh...
クリーンヒット＆ダウン！
We need to leave NGL and tell
the world what's happening...
[TV]　なんと　なんと！ 開けてビックリ
Whatever... Let's just run for it!
カストロ選手の 一方的な攻めが続きます！
Or we'll all be—
いっそ　このまま 何も解せぬまま…　死ぬか？
I-It's here!
気のせいかな？
More will be coming! Hold on, now...
君が消えたように見えたんだが…。
I said to capture the humans alive.
そうなんです！ 消えたんです！ 確かに　そう見えたんです！
We're supposed to deliver
them to the Queen fresh.
いや… それは表現が正しくないな。
A-A human face... What is that thing?! Fire...
目の前にいて 僕に蹴りをくれたはずの君が
Open fire!
…っていうのが 一番　近い表現だと思うんだが。
He grabbed my Orange Arrow, fastest of my Rainbow Arrows, with ease.
まだ何か違う気がする。
Huh? This is clearly visible.
違和感…　そうだな
The grunts couldn't see this?
何か基本的なものを 見落としている感じかな。
So the life energy
無駄だね　ただ逃げてばかりの お前では　謎は解けない。
that surrounds your body is
what fuels this weapon?
何にせよ　もう待たない 次で腕を頂くぞ。
You will make a magnificent
meal for the Queen...
その程度の使い手だったと 思うまでだ。
Balda!
出たぞ！　「虎咬拳」！ カストロが本気になったぜ！
O-Oh, no!
「虎咬拳」か… 達人なら大木を 真っ二つにすることも可能だ
I took a bite without thinking...
それに加え　ヒソカは　まだ カストロの能力に気づいていない
Zazan-sama will be angry again!
…って　俺も　まだ よく分かんねえけど！
You bastard!
このままだと やられっちまうぞ！ 行くぞ！
O-One moment...
あっ！
My hands are full.
フン　余裕か！ それとも罠のつもりか！
Take this!
こっちのな。
As always, you're a disgrace in battle. Zazan-sama...
ヒィ！ ヒソカの腕が！
Why don't you just drop what's in your hands? Oh!
ヒソカ選手の右腕が飛んだ！
You're right. We're going back. Hmm?
全てが自分の思い通りになると 思うなよ。
He probably has the nutritional value
of a thousand normal humans.
これも計算のうちさ。
Well done, Pike.
かつて　これほど苦戦する ヒソカ選手を
I am most grateful for your praise... You honor me!
見たことがあるでしょうか？
Don't forget the food.
これは恐らく 相当なダメージです！
Oh, yes...
フッフフフ…　なるほど 君の能力の正体は
I can't save him myself... I have to call for help!
さすがだな　その通りだ。
There's still... There's still time!
「ダブル」？　どういう意味だ？
Even if they take him, they
won't eat him immediately...
やっぱり　あれは 錯覚じゃなかったんだ！
Find a Hunter with a strong aura!
あいつの体が重なって見えたのは 現実だったのか
I must hurry back to the border!
一体　これは どういうことでしょうか？
Other Hunters should be there—
「ダブル」と呼ばれる　いわば もう１人の自分のことで
So much fun...
ドッペルゲンガーに会うと 本人が　疲労感や頭痛を 訴えることがあり
Hunting is so much fun!
これは　本人の「ダブル」が消滅すると 治まるといわれている。
Help!!
このことから「ダブル」は
Chimera Ant Nest
本人側から 何らかの力を吸い取って
Rocky Area
出現するものと推察されている。
Notify the Hunter Association!!
しかも彼は　それを 鍛錬により修得した。
It'll be dangerous. But could you accompany me?
君の忠告通り　逃げずに 目を凝らして見てみたよ。
We're pros. Miss interpreter...
すると　目の前の君は
Sorry, but we're in a hurry.
やっぱり　「消えた」が正しかった。
Yes. The horses can move a bit faster.
では　なぜ　さっきは その表現に違和感を感じたか。
They won't be fast enough.
消えたはずの君だが 気配は変わらず僕のそばにあり
I want you two to return to
the border, find the others, and get word to the Association. These creatures are dangerous.
むしろ　消える直前 増えたような気がしたから。
Got it. Be careful, Kite. Right.
君は消える前に 増えているんだよね。
If you can't keep up, I'll leave you behind. Right back at you.
フッ…　そこに気がつくとは 大したものだ。
All ready to go!
まず　「ダブル」が攻撃を仕掛け 私は死角に潜む。
Let's go.
それは　「ダブル」の攻撃を受けて 実感しただろう。
This is a bullet casing.
つまり　お前は　２人の私を 相手にしなければならない。
Nothing mechanical is allowed here, right? So the underground rulers of NGL
これが「念」によって完成した 真の「虎咬拳」
were manufacturing guns in addition to drugs.
名づけて「虎咬真拳」！
But judging by this...
おっと！ これは大番狂わせか!?
It wasn't done by a human.
２年前の勝者　ヒソカ選手が 絶体絶命だ！
Most likely, it was a Chimera Ant.
カストロ選手 ２年前のリベンジなるか!? 次は　左腕を頂く。
If the Chimera Ants are using guns...
それでも　まだ くだらぬ余裕を見せていたいか？
I hate to consider the possibility, but it's possible that NGL's underground rulers
うん　そうだなぁ。
have already been fed to the queen...
ちょっと　やる気　出て来たかな。
What will happen if Chimera Ants
are born with their genes?
恐るべき「ダブル」の使い手 カストロと　奇術師ヒソカ
NGL and Chimera Ants...
繰り広げられる激闘と その後に待ち受ける 想像を絶する結末を
The worst combination imaginable.
ゴンは　まだ知らない
This could create an unprecedented biohazard.